<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ramblings of Jimmy Zelinskie</title>
    <link>https://jzelinskie.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Ramblings of Jimmy Zelinskie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jzelinskie.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>P... what?</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/p-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/p-what/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that many software engineers either aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with other roles at their organization or are often confused by them. This is by no fault of their own because managerial roles differ from company to company and often people overextend their responsibilities to make up for a deficiency in the organization.
 It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that so many of them have roughly the same abbreviation: PM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A toolbox for your dotfiles</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/toolbox-for-your-dotfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/toolbox-for-your-dotfiles/</guid>
      <description>So you may have heard about this Docker™ thing. You know; it runs containers and all that jazz. You might think the container craze is only for developers that think this time they&amp;rsquo;ve finally understood operations. You&amp;rsquo;d be wrong however. I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain a simple trick that I use often when sshing into a remote machine for some old school sysadmin work.
Totally lost? If the title of this post seems unintelligible, fear not!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCI Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/oci-artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/oci-artifacts/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, CoreOS hired Antoine Legrand (@ant31). Antoine is an incredible engineer and a huge asset to the Kubernetes community; you may recognize him from many contributions, but most people probably would be familiar with a little project he started called Kubespray.
The first time I met Antoine, he had hacked together a demo of packaging up and storing Kubernetes resources into Quay. A fair bit after the initial demo, we decided it was worth pursuing for realsies and I helped Antoine through the process of making his demo a production grade feature for all Quay users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Lifecycle Manager</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/olm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/olm/</guid>
      <description>At KubeCon EU 2018, Red Hat eagerly announced the open sourcing of the Operator Framework. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of buzzword bingo these days, but being someone who helped originally pioneer the concept at CoreOS, I feel I can give a fair definition:
 An Operator is a Kubernetes pattern that is extending the Kubernetes control plane with a custom Controller and Custom Resource Definitions that add additional operational knowledge of an application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re not running vanilla Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/youre-not-running-vanilla-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/youre-not-running-vanilla-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Stop pretending it isn&amp;rsquo;t your own clumsy distribution. Seriously.
 Haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of &amp;ldquo;vanilla Kubernetes&amp;rdquo;? In the ever competitive age of selling Kubernetes, there seems to be a trend towards promising vendor neutrality. After all, the promise of Kubernetes is to free you from the tyranny of your cloud provider, right? It&amp;rsquo;s only natural that the mentality of avoiding lock-in be applied to Kubernetes itself. The community has arrived on the colloquial term &amp;ldquo;vanilla Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; to describe an installation of the only the upstream components as released by the Kubernetes project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please, don&#39;t recommend sourcing shell completion</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/dont-recommend-sourcing-shell-completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/dont-recommend-sourcing-shell-completion/</guid>
      <description>I recently got sick of opening a new tab and waiting seconds before my shell prompt showed up. In order to prevent my future self from wasting valuable seconds of my life, I went through the trouble of profiling my zsh configuration. After extensive use of zprof, I determined my bottleneck: sourcing command completion files, but only the ones that executed a program to get their contents.
Feast your eyes on the marvel that is modern software engineering:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jails, containers and their perceived security</title>
      <link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/jails-containers-and-their-perceived-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/jails-containers-and-their-perceived-security/</guid>
      <description>My scroll-wheel stops. Under my mouse, the typical HN comment:
 Docker&amp;rsquo;s just about packaging! Containers aren&amp;rsquo;t secure! Unlike like jails *strokes unix beard*
 The world&amp;rsquo;s full of interesting partial truths.
Docker did clue a lot of developers into the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s isolation primitives by providing a compelling developer experience. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for others to catch on, though. In my semi-recent foray with FreeBSD, I noticed that managing jails with iocage doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel too far off managing containers with docker.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>