<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker on jzelinskie</title><link>https://jzelinskie.com/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in docker on jzelinskie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © Jimmy Zelinskie 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzelinskie.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A toolbox for your dotfiles</title><link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/toolbox-for-your-dotfiles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/toolbox-for-your-dotfiles/</guid><description>So you may have heard about this Docker™ thing. You know; it runs containers and all that jazz. You might think the container craze is only for developers that think this time they&amp;rsquo;ve finally understood operations. You&amp;rsquo;d be wrong however. I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain a simple trick that I use often when sshing into a remote machine for some old school sysadmin work.
Totally lost? If the title of this post seems unintelligible, fear not!</description></item><item><title>OCI Artifacts</title><link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/oci-artifacts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/oci-artifacts/</guid><description>In 2016, CoreOS hired Antoine Legrand (@ant31). Antoine is an incredible engineer and a huge asset to the Kubernetes community; you may recognize him from many contributions, but most people probably would be familiar with a little project he started called Kubespray.
The first time I met Antoine, he had hacked together a demo of packaging up and storing Kubernetes resources into Quay. A fair bit after the initial demo, we decided it was worth pursuing for realsies and I helped Antoine through the process of making his demo a production grade feature for all Quay users.</description></item><item><title>Jails, containers, and their perceived security</title><link>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/jails-containers-and-their-perceived-security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzelinskie.com/posts/jails-containers-and-their-perceived-security/</guid><description>My scroll-wheel stops. Under my mouse, the typical HN comment:
Docker&amp;rsquo;s just about packaging! Containers aren&amp;rsquo;t secure! Unlike like jails *strokes unix beard*
The world&amp;rsquo;s full of interesting partial truths.
Docker did clue a lot of developers into the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s isolation primitives by providing a compelling developer experience. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for others to catch on, though. In my semi-recent foray with FreeBSD, I noticed that managing jails with iocage doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel too far off managing containers with docker.</description></item></channel></rss>